Nicolas Trinephi

 $oxed{\square}$ nicolas.trinephi@imperial.ac.uk

in /in/nicolastrinephi

❸ @live:nicolas_6754

① /ntrin

□ +1(949)-329-3603

% https://ntrin.github.io/

SUMMARY

Master's graduate in computational science with industry experience in deep learning algorithms applied to time series prediction using cloud data flow tools such as Databricks. A team player and results driven individual, I am searching for my next opportunity in data science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Teaching Assistant: Applied Computational Science *Imperial College London - London, UK (Remote)*

Sep 2020 - Present

Irvine, California

- Drove student learning by holding office hours to walk through solutions, methods and key concepts.
- Maintained academic excellence through mentoring 10 students on work habits and mental health with 1 on 1 meetings.

Data Science Intern June 2020 - Sep 2020

Wintershall DEA - Hamburg, Germany

- Streamlined project management and decision making by performing statistical and bi-variate analysis of 13 years
 of raw industrial oil production data on Azure Databricks using PySpark.
- Enabled more effective data comprehension and analysis by designing interactive visualization of the data in **Python** using **Plotly** and **HVplot**.
- Successfully forecast production rates with 99% accuracy by applying various LSTM recursive neural networks using Keras and MLflow.

Primary Mentor May 2019 - July 2019

UCL Mechanical Engineering Workshop - London, UK

- Ensured the success of projects such as the Hydrone Hydrogen Racecar by coaching students on design and technical platforms such as CAD and ARDUINO systems.
- Oversaw the safety of the workshop by supervising working students, facilitating machine operations, and training students in processes such as 3D printing and laser cutting.

EDUCATION

Master's of Science: Applied Computational Science

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020

Imperial College London - London, UK

- · Relevant Coursework: PyTorch Classification and Transfer Learning, Optimisation
- Thesis title: Deep Learning in Virtual Flow Metering

Bachelor's of Engineering (Hons): Mechanical Engineering with Finance *University College London - London, UK*

Sep 2016 - July 2019

Thesis title: Particle Suspensions in Microfluidic Applications

PROJECTS

Cifar10 Pv 2020

Imperial College London

Placed in the top 10 (score of 0.8) by applying **PyTorch** transfer learning with EfficientNet to classify over 10,000 images in a school Kaggle competition.

Conway's Game of Life in Parallel C++

2020

Imperial College London

Implemented Game of Life in parallel using C++ MPI and object oriented programming wherein the number of cores is adaptive to user's input with a post processing script developed in Python.

SKILLS

Languages Native English and French, conversational Spanish

Programming Python, C++, MATLAB, Bash, LATEX, HTML, MySQL, Dox BAT

Packages Keras, PyTorch, PySpark, MLflow, sklearn, XGBoost, Plotly, HoloViews, C++ MPI Technical Databricks, Apache Spark, Microsoft Office, GitHub, CATIA V. 5, Origin Pro